<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NodeBaseDevs – News About Testnet</title><link>/blog/news/</link><description>Recent content in News About Testnet on NodeBaseDevs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Ayaview Demo</title><link>/blog/2023/02/15/ayaview-demo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/15/ayaview-demo/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="nodebasedevs-is-introducing-ayaview">NodeBaseDevs is introducing &lt;strong>ayaview&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ayaview is a console based app to monitor your aya node, it will on-chain activity and system metrics.
It&amp;rsquo;s very light-weight, doesn&amp;rsquo;t comsume any resources, since it is not dependent on backend storages, like databases
to store blockchain history. Hence the application will only be monitoring the current blockchain state.
It&amp;rsquo;s fully configurable to monitor any validator node on any cosmos chain you are interested in.## Ayaview Demo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a live demo of a Sentry Node spinning up and playing catch-up to get synced to the current blockHeight.
It&amp;rsquo;s very fast syncing all blocks it has missed since it went down. As soon as it is caught up, normal activity
will assume with new blocks getting minted every 5s.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OE30hG7PC6A" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Blog: Launch of TheNodeBase Devs</title><link>/blog/2023/02/08/launch-of-thenodebase-devs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/08/launch-of-thenodebase-devs/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="nodebase-devs-site-is-born">NodeBase Devs site is born!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to the &lt;strong>Nodebase developers&lt;/strong> site. A place where we can share useful resources for Earthnode Operators
of the WorldMobile Chain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page was started to share material with the EarthNode community.As a early tester of WM Testnet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/earthnodechile">@earthnodechile&lt;/a> has early insights in how testnet is doing and came to the conclusion a lot of tooling is needed to help setup, run and monitor your EarthNode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this site I will also publish material about Cosmos SDK and write step-by-step guides all things related to running an Earthnode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Progress and opinion pieces on WM Testnet will be published to the blog section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The documentation section will contain material about running an earthnode and in-house developed tools to
assist Earthnode operators. More on that in the next blog.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Installation of Sentry Nodes</title><link>/blog/2023/02/08/installation-of-sentry-nodes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/08/installation-of-sentry-nodes/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="nodebase-devs-tools-released">NodeBase Devs tools released!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am releasing the initial nodebase tools package. You can learn more about it and how to download it in &lt;a href="/docs/tools">Tools&lt;/a>.
This package contains the sentry node setup and a few useful
scripts to assist in the setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in setting up a relay node, have a look at &lt;a href="/docs/getting-started">Getting Started&lt;/a> with all details on setting this. Some of the scripts in the tools are helpful when setting up a sentry node.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addtional info on validator setup will be added as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There will be an easy to follow step-by-step guide on setting up a relay available shortly in the &lt;a href="/docs/tuturial">Tutorial&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.TheNodeBaseDevs&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>