<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NodeBaseDevs – Documentation</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on NodeBaseDevs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Used Ports</title><link>/docs/configuration/ports/ports/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/configuration/ports/ports/</guid><description>
&lt;p>By default the follow ports are used by &lt;strong>aya&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>26656&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pnp networking port to connect to the tendermint network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On a validator this port needs to be exposed to sentry nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On a sentry node this port needs to be exposed to the open internet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This is the port validators and sentries use to communicate to each other&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>26657&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tendermint RPC port.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some tools, example querying tools, use this port to query blockchain status.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You should not directly expose this port.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This should be shield from the open internet.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>26658&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Out of process ABCI app&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This should be shielded from the open internet&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>29090&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the gRPC server port. This is used for gRPC server communication with&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cosmos SDK application layer. With this you can query banking, staking and - delegation information from Cosmos SDK.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Example, some monitoring services might use this communication mechanism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>since its much faster than RESTful.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This should be shielded from the open internet&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Some optional ports that might be used by &lt;strong>aya&lt;/strong> are as follows&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>26600&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/tendermint/tendermint/blob/master/docs/nodes/metrics.md">Prometheus&lt;/a> stats server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>System stats about the ayad process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Needs to be enabled in the config file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This should be shielded from the open internet&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>1317&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The REST server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for automated management of anything you can do with the CLI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This should be shieled from the open internet.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>More &lt;a href="https://docs.cosmos.network/main/core/grpc_rest">here&lt;/a> on endpoints&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: Monitoring tools that are installed use additional port, ex Grafana uses port 3000&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>IMPORTANT&lt;/strong>:
For ports 1317 and 26657, you way want to use them as a RESTful endpoint by proxy-ing them to an external interface via an http proxy like Nginx or Coddy. The idea is to treat them like a web service for RESTful requests to the RPC ports done over https. You may configure rate limiting on the http proxy or make request with user authentication using a web app. This way you are not exposing the ports directly and your node is protected from receiving too many request suddenly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>